

💌 ashishthakur913@qmail.com 📞 +1 5145463111 in ashish-kumar-kanwar/ 🗘 ashishthakur913

# **SUMMARY**

I love building new things from scratch and that is what I have been doing professionally for over 4 years. I am a tinkerer (DIY crafts, remote cars, LEGO) and that has always made me believe that I can build anything I desire. I am very passionate about writing code and bringing life-changing products to life. Aspire to work on projects which spin me out of comfort zone, to make me learn something new and to feed my curiosity.

## **SKILLS**

FRONT END: React, Redux, React Native, ImmutableJS, Typescript, Javascript/JQuery, UI/UX, HTML/CSS

BACK END: PHP, Golang, Java

DATABASES: MySQL, Redis, Elasticsearch, Memcache, Cassandra

**OPERATING SYSTEMS:** Mac OS, Linux, Ubuntu

### **EMPLOYMENT**

#### **Zomato**

Software Engineer · Oct. 2015 to Aug. 2018 · New Delhi, India

Art Of Where

Software Engineer · Oct. 2018 to Current · Montreal, Canada

## **PROJECTS**

- Worked on a product to detect real-time indoor location based on GPS and WiFi fingerprinting to provide location-based recommendations.
- Worked on Zomato's web platform frequently pushing new features live (front end and back end)
- $oldsymbol{\Theta}$  Implemented Google's AMP (Accelerated Mobile Pages) for Zomato's mobile web. This got featured on Google's blog post.
- Implemented PWA (Progressive Web App) for Zomato's mobile web with a small team of five.
- **6** Extensively worked on backend APIs for the mobile apps (IOS / Android).
- **6** Made various internal tools for the ad sales team helping the team derive more revenue.
- Built Zomato's new product "Zomato Gold" contributing towards both tech and product management.
- 1 Developed and maintained in house manufacturing management software at Art of Where
- Transitioned a monolith into microservices at Art Of Where

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Technology · Aug. 2011 to Aug. 2015 from Punjab Technical University

Masters in Computer Science · Sept. 2018 to Current

from Concordia University, Montreal